<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Reasons against the bill for erecting courts of conscience</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28691</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12648699</idno>
  <idno type="VID">199606</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240951671</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R476</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">12648699</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28691)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 199606)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 775:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Reasons against the bill for erecting courts of conscience</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.) ;  20 x 33 cm. </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1670?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Broadside.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Small claims courts --  England.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Courts baron and courts leet.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:199606:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>REASONS</hi> Against passing the BILL prepared, concerning Writs of CERTIORARI.</head>
            <p>IT is alledged in the Bill, that by means of Writs of <hi>Certiorari,</hi> whereby Indictments, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are removed into the Court of Kings-Bench, Offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders escape Unprosecuted, and Unpunished, and the King loseth the Fines which would be imposed, were not such Indictments removed.</p>
            <p>And also intended to be Enacted in the said Bill, That no <hi>Certiorari</hi> shall be granted but upon Motion in Court, and the Cause for granting thereof, to be specified in the Writ, and the <hi>Certiorari</hi> shall onely be delivered at the Quarter Sessions of the Peace in open Court, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That all Indictment, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> removed by <hi>Certiorari,</hi> shall be effectually prosecuted and brought to Trial or Judgment; or otherwise determined with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the space of two Terms, and within the County Pallatines, within six months after the <hi>Certiorari</hi> returned, or else <hi>Procedendo's ex Officio &amp; gratis,</hi> shall be made, and for default of making the <hi>Procedendo's;</hi> The Master of the Office to forfeit for the first Offence, forty pounds, and for every other such Offence one hundred pounds.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>It is humbly conceived,</hi> That the Allegations in the Preamble of this Bill, are grounded upon a mistake; There being no delay in the proceedings against Offenders in the Court of Kings-Bench, process being duly made out, and Offenders more speedily and duly punished then at the Sessions of Peace, or any Inferiour Court whatsoever: For that forthwith after every Indictment, is removed into the said Court, Process are thereupon duly made out from Term to Term against the Offenders, until they are Out-lawed, if they do not appear; If they do appear, they must plead the next Term af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, or else Judgment may be entred against them: If they do plead the Prosecutor may carry it to Trial, and be allowed the third part of the Fine if they be Convicted, by vertue of a Privy Seal enrolled in Court. If the Prosecutor doth not try it, the King doth not lose his Fine, for unless the Defendent try it himself the next Assizes after his plea, or submit to a Fine, Process are duly made out until he be Out-lawed; and after the Out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lary is reversed, he must try the said Indictment, or otherwise legally discharge it.</p>
            <p>That the King doth not lose his Fines by reason of the removal of Indictments; For that more Fines come to the Kings use imposed upon Offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders in the Kings-Bench, upon Indictments removed, then out of all the Inferiour Courts, though not one Indictment of a hundred, is removed into the said Court.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>As to what</hi> is first intended to be Enacted by the said Bill: That no <hi>Certiorari</hi> shall be made, but upon motion made in open Court, and delivered at the Quarter Sessions of the Peace, <hi>&amp;c<seg rend="sup">.</seg>
               </hi>
            </p>
            <div type="part">
               <p>
                  <hi>It is Answered,</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>That</hi> except <hi>Certiorari's</hi> be made in the Vacation time (without Motion in Court) Persons can have little or no benefit by them: For that the Quarter Sessions of the Peace by Law, are to be kept in the Vacation time, and before Motion can be made in Court (in Term time) for the Writ, they shall be adjudged and punished without remedy: And besides, the great charge and trouble the persons will be put to in their Motions, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> will prove a Remedy as bad, if not worse then the Disease. As for Example, A man may be Indicted in the beginning of a Summer Vacation, for forcible Entry or Detainer, by one who pretendeth Title to his House or Land, and turned out of Possession, and lose all his Summer profit of his Land, and can have no remedy before <hi>Michaelmas</hi> Term. Or if a man be Indicted at a Private Sessions for a forcible Entry, he shall be turned out of possession, and have no remedy, unless he can have a <hi>Certiorarie</hi> in the Vacation time: And further, the charge of a <hi>Certiorari</hi> by Motion in Court upon cause shewed, will be at least a treble charge to the Subject; Nay probably, six times more than now it is.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>As to what is next</hi> intended to be Enacted <hi>(viz.)</hi> That all Indictments, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> shall be prosecuted and brought to Trial within two Terms, <hi>&amp;c. It is Answered,</hi> That there are no Assizes between <hi>Easter</hi> and <hi>Trinity</hi>-Term, nor between <hi>Michelmas</hi> and <hi>Hillary</hi> Term, for Trial of such Indictments; and Process cannot be made out but from Term to Term; and if a special Plea be pleaded, it cannot come to Issue, to be tried in so short a time.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>As to the last Clause</hi> in the Bill for the making out <hi>Procedendo's ex Officio &amp; gratis. It is Answered,</hi> That after an Indictment is returned and filed on Record in the Court of Kings-Bench, which is immediately done upon the return, it cannot be sent back by <hi>Procedendo;</hi> for Process are thereupon immediately made out, and the party may be Out-lawed, and no Record to warrant it. And if the Clerk of the Crown shall make <hi>Procedendo's ex Officio &amp; gratis,</hi> and be at the charge of sending Messengers into the several-Counties to the Justices, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> with the Indictments; It may prove a charge greater than the benefit of his Office.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And it is</hi> further desired to be observed; That the issuing forth of Writ of <hi>Certiorari,</hi> out of the Court of Kings-Bench, for removing of Indict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> from the Sessions of Peace, and other Inferiour Courts, hath been alwayes accounted an undoubted Right and Liberty, belonging unto the Subject, as their Appeal; and that no <hi>Certiorari</hi> is made, but by warrant from one of the Judges of the said Court; though antiently, and till of late, such Writ were made without any warrant, as commonly as Writ of Latitat, and such like mean process.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>That it is the undoubted Prerogative of the King,</hi> to sue and prosecute Offenders in what Court he pleases; Especially proper in the Court of Kings-Bench, where his Learned Councel most usually attend, and where onely Writs of Outlary can be made against Criminal Offenders, for want of Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And it is to be observed, that no Clerk of the Assize, or Clerk of the Peace, do make out Process against Offenders upon Indictments to Outlary▪ notwithstanding they do not appear; neither do any of the said Clerks certifie any Records of Outlary, into the Court of Kings-Bench, as by Law they ought to do: Neither can they make out Process out of their own Counties, in case the Offenders live or remove into other Counties which frequently happens; but Process out of the Kings-Bench can be made against Offenders all the Realm over.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>That for want of Certiorari's,</hi> The Justices of the Peace, may if they please assume an Arbitrary power whereby the people may suffer for want of their Appeal.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>That the Peers of the Realm,</hi> and their Tenants may suffer much for want of these Writs: For though most of the Peers are in the Commissions of the Peace, yet they seldom appear at the Sessions: Besides, their Lands lie dispersed in several Counties. The Peers are like more especially to be preju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diced in case of forcible Entries, wherein Justices of the peace have power to give possession of Estates without controul, except <hi>Certioraries</hi> be grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed aswell in the Vacation, as in Term time.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>